Travis Prall

Phoenix, AZ 85083 ↔ Phone: (602) 810-4821 ↔ Email: <u>js21imu8g@relay.firefox.com</u> ↔ <u>Travisprall.com</u>

OBJECTIVE: Experienced scientist, engineer, healthcare professional and military veteran, with years of experience engineering software and databases, seeking a challenging position as a **Software Engineer**.

QUALIFICATIONS

- Laboratory Testing & Analysis
- Research & Evaluation
- Python Programming Proficient
- Training & Development
- SQL Database Architect
- Networking
- Docker Proficiency
- Data Analytics
- Detail Oriented, Problem Solver
- Software deployment

- Innovative designs
- Authored 300+ apps
- Leadership & Management
- Skilled with Windows and Linux
- Insurance, Medicare, & Medicaid

EDUCATION

 B.S. in Clinical Laboratory Science, DeVry University, 2018 B.S. in Animal Physiology & Behavior, Arizona State University, 2014

Experience

- Python
- Data Science
- Javascript
- React
- C
- C++
- Html
- CSS

- SOL
- MySQL
- PostgreSOL
- InfluxDB
- MongoDB
- NoSQL

- Docker
- Numpy
- Pandas
- Diango
- Scripting
- Linux

PROJECTS

- For a demo of a full stack webserver written and hosted by me visit https://www.travisprall.com
- Created system for managing, controlling, and tracking environmental systems for air conditioners, doors, and windows. Monitors temperature, humidity, energy consumption, sun movement, luminance, and ultraviolet energy. Adjust temperature based on occupancy and anticipated need. Resulted in 30% less energy consumption.
- Created a system for tracking tasks that need to be done with an economic feedback point system. Points per tasked changed based on need, frequency done, and time overdue. Analyzes and attempts to motivate users.
- Created a complex system for tracking movement of personnel from room to room. Adjusts lights, temperature, and notifications as needed.
- Created a security system that uses detection of wifi and bluetooth, motion, and visual machine learning from TensorFlow.
- Numerous lighting effects and automations for IOT devices.
- See https://github.com/Travis-Prall/resume for more information.

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Medical Laboratory Scientist

Honor Health Phoenix AZ FEB 2019-PRESENT

Certified Medical Laboratory Scientist (ASCP 266499); responsible to perform complex laboratory tests on blood, body fluids, cells, and tissues. Identify bacteria, parasites, and other microorganisms, analyze chemical content of fluids, and cross match blood for transfusion and aseptically prepare blood products. Understands specimen factors that can affect the accuracy of laboratory testing and ensures the integrity of the specimen through the testing process. Assist, train and orient new staff and students in their respective lab discipline

Certified Pharmacy Technician

Fry's Pharmacy, Phoenix AZ DEC 2013-FEB 2019

• Licensed Pharmacy Technician (#T039025 AZ); assists 3,000+ patients monthly in a fast-paced pharmacy with 8+ technicians and 2-fulltime Pharmacist on staff in a CLIA environment. Accurately calculates quantities & dosages,

Travis Prall

prepares labels, and counts & administers 300-500 prescription per day. Serves as the only non-Pharmacist for oversight of the Controlled Substances Prescription Monitoring Program (PMP). Trains & orients new staff and clinical interns, while providing patient-centered care. Actively researches and resolves patient inquires & concerns—escalating as appropriate. Manages pharmaceutical supply orders, inventory tracking, prescription data entry, insurance verification, billing, and payment processing (private insurance, Medicare, & Medicaid). Ensures state & federal regulatory, safety, and accrediting agency compliance.

Contract Specialist (Active Duty)

United States Air Force, Tyndall AFB, FL DEC 2000-APR 2005

Researched and analyzed marketing trends, supply sources, and trade information in accordance with DoD & Air Force standards. Evaluated contractor compliance with bonding, insurance, and tax requirements. Managed acquisitions, supplies, and service requirements for approximately \$5.3 million dollars in contracts over 4-year period. Oversaw bid solicitations, assessed quotes & proposals, and negotiated contracting terms. Resolved payment issues for \$100-dollars in contracts—saved \$1.5K in interest payments. Authored the contract close-out spreadsheet with 10-years of projected data included to ensure 100% accountability. Led & managed members of the Base Honor Guard team---coordinated events, trainings, and maintained accountability. Managed AirForce Robotics Laboratory.

ADDITIONAL LEADERSHIP & MANAGEMENT WORK EXPERIENCE

Landlord Self-Owned, JAN 2002-Present

Phoenix AZ

Manages and maintains at least two tenant properties.

Preventative Maintenance Manager DSW Inc. & HDS Inc.,

Phoenix AZ

JAN 1998-MAR 2000

• Led & managed a team of 10+ facilities maintenance staff members---interviewed, hired, and trained team members, managed schedules, addressed personnel concerns, and conducted feedback evaluations.

VOLUNTEER WORK

- Trail Host (Educator), Phoenix Zoo, 2016-2017
- Field Technician, Arizona Fish and Game, 2016-2017